♪ Here we are going far ♪
♪ to save all that we love ♪
♪ If we give all we’ve got ♪
♪ we will make it through ♪
♪ Here we are like a star ♪
♪ shining bright
on your world today ♪
♪ Make evil go away ♪
♪ Code Lyoko we’ll
withstand it all ♪
♪ Code Lyoko be there
when you call ♪
♪ Code Lyoko we
will stand real tall ♪
♪ Code Lyoko
stronger after all ♪
Interface transfer activated.
Virtual memory activated.
Code management configured.
Scanners activated and verified.
Targeting OK.
This time, it’s gonna work!
Ready, Aelita?
Ready.
Here we go.
It’s working!
Ready?
Go on, Kiwi! Go on, fetch!
Anyone seen Jeremie
this morning?
I think he spent the night
in the laboratory.
He was working on
something “really important.”
Hmm.
Aelita!
Hiyah!
Hey, I thought it was timeout!
Oh! Guess I forgot!
Hey, guys!
Guess what I did last night!
Let’s see, now…
It’s got something to do with
materializing…Aelita?
That’s right.
Say, how did you guess, Odd?
Well, guys, I finally did it.
I decided to tackle the problem
in a different way.
You wouldn’t believe it, but…
Well, tell us!
Did you do it or not?
I sure did!
Hm…
You materialized a test tube.
No, airhead!
Look inside, will you?
A hair?
You mean you materialized one hair?
Yep. That’s right, Odd.
To be exact, it’s a hair of…
Aelita’s.
What? A real hair?
But how did you manage that?
Well, I chose a hair because
it’s a simple anatomical structure,
but which contains aelita’s
complete genetic computer code
according to a well-known fractal
whose recurrences are comparable
to the genetic code of a human,
which enabled me to make
a physiological number transfer
onto one part of the program
already pretargeted and defragmented.
And that’s that.
Simple enough, right?
Do you follow?
No.
No, it’s not simple enough,
or no you don’t follow?
Uh…no means that
we take your word for it.
-Mhmm.
No problem.
It’ll become clear when
Aelita’s here in flesh and blood.
Better get ready, Aelita.
Okay, Jeremie.
Huh?
You’re gonna materialize her now?
What do you think?
I’m not gonna wait until next year.
The hair was just a test
before we do the whole thing.
Listen, making a hair appear is one thing.
Materializing Aelita is not the same.
Look, you want to spend
your whole life fighting XANA?
Once Aelita’s been materialized,
we can unplug XANA once and for all
and lead normal lives.
So I say it’s worth trying.
How can that be?
I planned everything so perfectly.
You’re almost there, Jeremie.
In a few days, you’ll be all set.
You’ll see.
Hey, come on, you guys.
If we don’t materialize in a
couple of minutes in the classroom,
we’re not gonna last a few days!
(SCHOOL BELL RINGS)
You know, I’d have sworn
that it’ll work this time.
But…
if the computer gene code of the hair
gives you enough information
to find the parameters for materialization,
well then what’s the problem?
I wish I knew.
I’m doing something wrong.
The only way to find out
is to start over.
No, don’t do that!
You’re only a hair’s breadth away!
(SNICKERS)
Can you ever be serious, Odd?
By the way, Odd,
speaking of hair,
your dog sheds
an awful lot of them.
most of them end up
on my bed, too.
What’s the big deal
about two or three hairs?
Two or three?
With all the hairs he sheds,
I could knit you another Kiwi!
Hello.
Did you say dog?
Oh, I really adore dogs.
Hey, can I sit down?
No.
You know, I’m so crazy about dogs
that I’m ready to keep my mouth shut
about the one Odd’s hiding in his room.
That is, if you promise
to be nicer to me, of course.
Listen, Sissi, I’m warning you,
if you say anything about Kiwi, I’ll--
You okay, Yumi?
There we are.
It’s nothing serious.
The cut isn’t very deep.
Here. Put this on it, please.
It’s incredible.
I barely squeezed the glass.
They’re pretty fragile, I guess.
Fragile, huh?
We’re not talking about venetian crystal.
Lunchroom plastic’s more like it.
Anyway, I know what I’m in for
if I get on your nerves.
(CELL PHONE RINGS)
What?
On our way.
I don’t believe it. It’s a disaster!
What is?
I was trying to figure out
why the materialization didn’t work,
and I realized that
Aelita’s program is all full of bugs.
When I materialized the hair, I…
I hit a button I shouldn’t have,
and so I…I damaged
the annex programs.
Annex? That doesn’t sound so bad.
That’s what you think.
The part of the program linking Aelita
to the towers is screwed up.
If Aelita enters the Lyoko code,
she’ll be completely reformatted!
Meaning?
She’ll disappear forever.
You know, Jeremie,
a program can be debugged.
We can do it together.
What if XANA attacks
before we’re done?
That means you gotta work fast, Jeremie.
Okay. Make up a story
to tell to the teachers.
I’m not leaving this computer
until I’ve solved the problem.
You think they can do it?
What do you think?
We’ve got two geniuses at work.
(BARKING)
Hey, Odd, if you don’t get Kiwi
to calm down, they’re gonna find him.
Hey, quiet, Kiwi!
You heard me, quiet down!
(BARKING)
What’s the matter?
Did you smell something?
Kiwi!
Whoa!
Did you do that?
Well, maybe it was
a ball that did it.
And you, of course,
didn’t see anything.
I couldn’t have seen anything, Jim,
because…I wasn’t here!
Maybe so.
But since all the rooms
are off-limits during the day,
how come you knew
about the window?
Ulrich, clean up your bed.
There’s hair all over it.
What happened?
Everything’s cool.
Jim didn’t spot Kiwi.
But it was close.
Kiwi will have to
stay with Jeremie for a while.
Why don’t you scan
the STR connection blocks?
I already did.
That’s not where I went wrong.
Stop chewing my slipper!
Oh. Sorry, Aelita.
I was talking to the dog.
When he’s around,
it’s hard to concentrate.
What is it?
Oh, nothing!
Give that back to me! Give it back!
That dog.
He took my…my handkerchief.
(BARKING)
Oh, take him away, please!
(HOWLING)
Oh, that mutt.
I was just passing by, and…
I always said Sissi’s head
was full of plaster.
I’m heading for the lab.
With the dog barking
and the school falling apart,
I can’t work in my room.
See ya.
I hope he finds the right solution
before XANA attacks again.
I’ll see you guys tomorrow.
Hello? Anybody home?
All these things happening
are really weird.
First, Yumi’s glass breaks,
then the window gets shattered,
and now the ceiling.
You think it’s XANA?
Maybe it’s just coincidence.
Maybe.
I’m back, Aelita.
Oh, no. I don’t believe it. Not now!
Okay, we can get back to work.
Aelita?
Are you there?
It’s XANA!
He’s launched an attack!
Are you…are you sure?
Oh, no!
It can’t be! Not now!
I’ve never seen such a thing
in my entire career.
You think humidity
could’ve caused it, sir?
I don’t know.
It doesn’t look very damp.
The dog!
I’ve been after him
for a long time!
What the…
Whoa!
Jim, we have to
evacuate the building.
Mhmm.
It’s XANA for sure.
Oh, yeah. It’s him.
How does he do it?
Your guess is as good as mine.
But you heard Sissi.
Kiwi began barking
just before the ceiling fell.
That might be a lead.
With the window was the same.
Maybe Kiwi can
feel the attacks coming.
Or maybe he can feel them
like a kind of ultrasound.
Jeremie.
XANA alert.
That’s what we thought.
Warn Yumi.
Be right there.
It’s real this time.
XANA has woken up.
Your attention, please.
Due to a danger
of structural accident,
please evacuate the building calmly,
and leave the immediate area.
No one will be permitted
to enter the building
until further notice.
Kiwi! He’s in Jeremie’s room.
I’ll go and get him.
See you at the lab.
(CELL PHONE RINGS)
Hello?
Hi, Ulrich.
What?
Uh, I’m not really ready yet.
Okay, I’ll hurry.
Kiwi? Where are you? Come on!
Diggity dog!
Huh?
Didn’t anyone ever
teach you to knock, huh?
Didn’t you hear the principal?
You gotta get out!
The whole building may collapse!
Come on, cut it out!
No, I swear! I’m not joking!
Hey, what's wrong with your dog?
(RUMBLING)
About face.
Ulrich!
How are things going over there?
There are cracks
in the school building.
It may cave in.
XANA’s using some kind of
ultrasound system.
Ultrasound, huh? That’s possible.
He could be using
the electrical sockets.
Listen, he might attack the factory.
Odd’s on his way,
and I’ve warned Yumi.
Let’s hope XANA gives me
enough time to repair my program.
Yes, Odd.
Huh?
I’m stuck, right.
With Milly and Tamiya
if you must know.
The firefighters will be here any minute,
so I can’t meet you right now.
No, don’t wait. Go to Lyoko.
(BARKING)
No!
Odd! Odd!
No time to lose, Jeremie.
But I’m not finished
fixing the program!
Odd is in danger.
Transfer me right now.
(BARKING)
What’s going on?
Transfer Ulrich.
Scanner Ulrich.
Virtualization.
Ulrich…
Aelita.
Shh. They’re here.
There’s nothing on my
holomap for now.
Things seem pretty calm.
That’s not what the pulsations say.
If we follow them, they’re bound to
lead us to the tower XANA’s activated.
Mhmm.
What happened here?
Odd…
He’s stuck inside.
With Milly and Tamiya.
Oh, why aren’t they here yet!
Look, we can’t stay here.
We’ve got to cross over
to the other side!
Are you out of your mind, Odd?
It’s at least a 10-meter drop!
Trust me, okay?
I can’t tell you how yet,
but we’re gonna make it.
In the meantime, we’ve got to
get across where we’ll be safe.
No!
No problem!
Your turn now!
We’re coming to the parallel pass.
Aah!
Jeremie, how many
life points do I have?
Hold on! 70! Uh, no. 60!
Make up your mind, Jeremie!
I gotta know! Take cover, Aelita!
I can’t do a million things at once!
Dodge the lasers,
and you won’t have to keep count!
Yumi, immediate departure.
Ulrich and Aelita need your help!
Okay, here we go.
Transfer Yumi.
Scanner Yumi.
Virtualization.
The pulsations are separating
in two directions now!
Then head east.
The monsters you managed
to dodge before aren’t very far away.
Okay, Jeremie.
We’ll try to find another path.
Too late.
Yumi!
Need a hand around here?
Hiyah!
Impact!
Here we go!
There!
There you go.
Okay, your turn, Milly!
No, I’ll never make it!
Sure you will! Come on!
A-a-a-a-h!
Good going, girls.
Okay, let’s get out of here.
I don’t believe it!
Watch out!
Yah! Impact!
Y-a-a-a-h!
XANA’s pulled out all the stops.
We’re not gonna last long, Jeremie.
Jeremie, do you read me?
Jeremie!
A little patience, guys!
I’m almost done!
Okay, Aelita can
enter the program now.
It’s safe!
We’re all set.
Hang on, Aelita.
I’m starting up the repair program.
Just in time, too.
It’s getting kinda hot around here.
Here we go!
No! This can’t be!
Jeremie, I’ve got to deactivate the tower.
No! Give me a little more time!
I’ll start over again!
Jeremie…
You know there’s no choice.
You’ll be reformatted
and disappear, Aelita!
I can’t let you do that!
Are you ready for one last run?
No, Aelita!
Don’t do it!
I’ll be in front.
Impact!
Hiyah!
No! Don’t do it, Aelita!
Goodbye, Jeremie.
No!
Aelita!
Return to the past…now.
Jeremie, it wasn’t your fault.
It was. And all that…
for a strand of hair.
Hey, the hair!
Jeremie, didn’t you say that the hair
contained Aelita’s entire genetic code?
Her computer code, yes, but…
Is it possible to reverse things,
and recreate Aelita’s code
from the strand of her hair?
Here we go.
It works! The codes are getting restored!
Let’s hope that…
Jeremie!
I’m ready for my materialization now!
Aelita!
Aelita! It worked!
Yeah!
Jeremie, did I miss something?
Why is there water on your face?
I’ll tell you later, Aelita.
This time, we only missed…
by a hair!
(LAUGHTER)
CLOSED CAPTIONING PROVIDED BY
REDDIT.COM/R/CODELYOKO